The Bible is not a rule book for your
life. If you reading the Bible today and
it's not clicking, it's because you're
reading it the wrong way. Most people
read this like a rule book for life. It
governs this life and the next. That is
not what the Bible is. The Bible is a
collection of stories [music] that was
written down and recorded at a time when
nobody could read or write and paper
didn't exist. And the Bible [music]
ain't just stories, they are the epic
interactions of humanity with the
divine. Like Jacob, who was so
hardheaded he slept with a rock for a
pillow and fought an angel that he saw
descending and ascending from heaven on
a ladder. King David, the 13-year-old
boy who killed a 7-ft 2 Goliath with a
rock and a slingshot at age 13. Think
about the faith of Elijah's widow who
gave her last oil and flour to make a
cake for the prophet instead of eating
it with her and her son during the
famine in the land. Think about the
prophet Jonah who was told to go to
Nineveh and book passage elsewhere, got
swallowed up by a whale. Guess where he
was when the whale spit him out? On the
beach at Nineveh. Not supposed to be
recited by verse and chapter and book,
it's supposed to be written on the
tablet of your heart just like it is on
mine. Thanks to my dad, Mike Fells, who
raised me with this book. He put it in
my head as a young child and you can see
the fruit bearing forth in my life. And
yes, the Bible has been changed and
altered to control and influence you in
certain ways, but they cannot remove the
God element. That thing within you, your
conscience, your intuition, that let you
connect with the courage of David or the
fear of Jonah or the brashness of Jacob.
These are the things you have to pick
out. You do not need to look for the
rules, you need to look for the
reflection. Jesus came to make you free
[music] from the law. The church came to
impose the law. And the modern church
that exists today is exactly what Jesus
said not to do. You shall not be like
the Pharisees who pray on the street
corner with phylacteries to make a big
show of it. The Bible is not a rule book
for your life. It is a collection of
stories that was written down and
preserved to leave breadcrumbs to lead
you back to the divine which is within
you. My name is Joe Fells. I've been
following Jesus my entire life and the
world doesn't recognize it cuz they
don't recognize Jesus, because they read
the Bible incorrectly.